thoughts.com 2008-12-16

# Privacy Policy

**Thoughts.com Privacy Policy**

Thoughts.com is an Internet blogging site that allows its users to set up individual personal blogs that can be shared and viewed by networks of friends and family. Thoughts.com bloggers can view each other's blogs and correspond with other bloggers throughout the site. Users can post their ideas, photos, videos, diaries, experiences, various comments, and describe their interests through blogs. Thoughts.com users can modify their personal information at any time and have the ability to manage how other Thoughts.com users and the service communicates with them. Thoughts.com clearly has its blogging user's best interests in mind regarding their privacy and security. Should you feel that you have any questions regarding the Thoughts.com policy on privacy, please feel free to contact us at <http://www.thoughts.com/site/contact_form>.

**Personal information we may collect**

Thoughts.com may gather personal information when you register for your blogging membership, service, or otherwise willingly provide such personal information. Thoughts.com may store personal information collected from you with information from other Thoughts.com services or perhaps third parties in order to provide improved user know-how, including customizing content for our members.

Thoughts.com may utilize cookies and other technology to improve your Internet blogging experience and to study how you use Thoughts.com in order to make progressive changes to the quality of our services we provide in the future. Thoughts.com servers, by design, record information when you visit our blogging site or when you use some of the products designed by Thoughts.com. This may include the IP address, URL, browser type, language, and the date and time of your application.

**How we may use your information**

At times, Thoughts.com may utilize personal information to provide the services you have asked for. This may include services that display customized blogging content and advertising.

Additionally, we may also utilize the personal information you voluntarily provide for reviewing, to do research with in order to operate and improve our services for the Thoughts.com blogging community.We may share grouped non-personal information from your registration as a whole, or part, with third parties outside of Thoughts.com for research and other statistical uses.

Should Thoughts.com use third parties to support us in processing your personal information, we oblige them to use the same privacy conditions and matter that we do at Thoughts.com at the minimum. They must comply with our privacy policy principals and any other suitable privacy and safekeeping procedures.

Thoughts.com may share information with third parties in limited conditions, including when complying with legal procedures, preventing fraud or impending harm, and ensuring the protection of our network of bloggers and services. Thoughts.com processes personal information on our servers in the United States of America as well as other countries and principalities. In addition to this, Thoughts.com processes personal information on a server outside your own country of residence.

**Your options**

Whenever possible, Thoughts.com provides its users with choices when we ask for personal information. You have the right to refuse entering your personal information to us and/or reject cookies in your computer's browser; however, some of our features or services at Thoughts.com may not be able to work for you if you choose to decline them. Here at Thgoughts.com, we strive to provide our users with the best possible Internet services and we work hard to provide our bloggers access to their personal information when they request it. We work diligently to provide our users the chance to update such data if it is incorrect and delete it, when realistically possible to do so.

**Promotions, contests and giveaways**

Occasionally, Thoughts.com intends to sponsor contests. Users wishing to take part in these giveaways and other promotions may be asked to provide Thoughts.com with personal information including name, age, home address, phone contact and email address or to answer questions in order to take part in such contests. Rarely, but in some instances, Thoughts.com may need to transfer a user's personal information to certain advertising partners that you have openly requested to obtain information from. It will be obvious at the point of compilation who is collecting the user's personal information and whose privacy statement will be relevant.

**Additional disclosures**

Any personal information voluntarily entered to any blog at Thoughts.com, including user videos and photos and any other personal identification information that is displayed publicly to people in order to assist user communication in the Thoughts.com blogging community is done so, completely at the user's discretion. Thoughts.com may use its user's email address to send updates and other types of communications with its user's. Users may choose not to take delivery of these emails by electing to do so upon registration.

All Thoughts.com bloggers and users must fully understand that whenever you willingly post public information to blogs or any other public forums that that information can be accessed by the public and can in turn be used by those people to send you unsolicited communications.

**Links**

Thoughts.com blogs and may contain links to outside sites. Thoughts.com is not accountable for the privacy policies, content, and/or situations on other Internet sites. When linking to another site, bloggers will want to be certain that they are fully aware of that site's privacy policies and practices. The Thoughts.com privacy policy only keeps track of information collected on Thoughts.com itself.

**Privacy policy updates or other changes**

As Thoughts.com progresses or situations in development arise, changes to our privacy policy may come about. Should changes be made, we will post them in complete form on our site to make Thoughts.com users conscious of what the changes are. This will allow the Thoughts.com community to continually become aware of what information Thoughts.com collects, how it is used, and when it would be disclosed. All Thoughts.com bloggers and users are bound by any minor changes to the policy when they use the site after those changes have been posted. What's more, if we are going to use users' individually identifiable information in a method considerably different from what is stated at the time of compilation, we will notify by posting a notice on our website for an adequate amount of time or through email communications.
